

Shivam Goyal

Al Researcher | Deep Learning Enthusiast | Flutter Dev

I'm a budding Data Scientist who tries to get insights about what's beneficial for a business and what's not by simply applying machine learning & statistical analysis on the pre-analysis data. I do love to keep the design and development process closer together, creating experiences designed for users first, while also taking care of business and brand needs.

shivamgoyal1899@gmail.com

(+91) 90122 18994



shivamgoyal.tk

in linkedin.com/in/ShivamGoyal1899

EDUCATION

B.E. Computer Engineering

Thapar Institute of Engineering & Technology

2018 - Present 8.63 CGPA

Senior Secondary

Divine Educational Institute

2017 93.80 %

PROJECTS

Gesture Controlled Robotic Arm

• This project focuses on replicating your hand movements to the robotic arm through deep learning model and openCV. So, no extra sensors are required except a laptop with a working webcam.

CreditCard Fraud Detection System ☑

A Credit Card Fraud Detection System based on Machine Learning algorithms. It sorts out fraudulent transactions from genuine transactions.

Movie Recommendation Engine **Z**

• It's a Movie Recommender System that predicts which movies you should watch next on the basis of your liked/last watched movie.

Affekt [Emotion Recognition App]

• Using Microsoft's Emotion API, Affekt can detect the emotion of the people in an image or even in real time!

WORK EXPERIENCE

ML & Flutter Developer

Enappd

06/2019 - Present

Bengaluru

- Developed Flutter Apps based on ML Algorithms.
- Conducted Bootcamps on Python & Git.

Contact: Abhijeet Rathore - fb/rathoreabhijeet

DSC Lead

Google Developer Student Club

06/2019 - Present

Digital Marketing Internship

Inkpothub

02/2019 - Present

Patiala

Contact: Rishabh Sahani - fb/rishabh.sahni.3956

Android TV [ADT-2] Development Team Google Developers

01/2019 - Present

Contact: Loic Wei Yu Neng - loicweiyuneng@google.com

SKILLS

Data Analytics Python Web Development **DBMS** Git VCS Data Structures PHP Blockchain

JavaScript

C / C++

Scratch

ACHIEVEMENTS

picoCTF (2018)

Bagged Global Rank 1415 in picoCTF 2018 with a score of 6435 among 16143 teams worldwide.

Google HashCode (2019)

Bagged Global Rank 945 & All India Rank 33 in Google HashCode Online Qualification Round 2019 with a score of 680469 among 6671 teams worldwide.

ORGANIZATIONS

ORION'19 - InterYear TechFest TIET

WebMaster, App Developer & Tech Team Member

IEI Thapar Students' Chapter

WebMaster & Tech Team Member

MaRS TIFT

WebMaster & Tech Team Member

Facebook Developer Circle

GeeksForGeeks

Founder | TIET Student Chapter

MAJOR CERTIFICATES

Mathematics for Machine Learning Specialization Imperial College London

Applied Data Science with Python Specialization University of Michigan

Machine Learning

Stanford University

LANGUAGES

English

German

Full Professional Proficiency Limited Working Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Punjabi

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Blogging

Solo Travelling

LAN Gaming

Event Management

Graphic Designing